Roberto Esparza

Web Developer

ABOUT ME

I have over 8 years of experience in web development, for small agencies and big companies.

I'm passionate about solving problems and bring value to the company.

I love to maintaining code consistency, helping others, and learning new technologies.

in /Roberto-Esparza

/RobertoEsp

www.robertoesparza.dev

robert_esparza@hotmail.com

EDUCATION

Bachelors Degree in Computer Systems Engineering

Jan 2010 - Jun 2015

- Durango Technological Institute (Instituto Tecnológico de Durango)
- Durango, México

SKILLS

- Team worker
- Love to learn
- Critical Thinking
- Team Health Check
- Clean Code
- React JS
- TypeScript
- Tailwind CSS
- Redux
- GraphQL
- Node JS
- Jest
- React Testing Library
- A/B Testing
- AWS
- SQL
- Mongo DB
- Docker

WORK EXPERIENCE

WIZELINE

Software Engineer

Guadalajara, México 2021 - Actual

Working as a consultant has made me more perceptive of the opportunities a project has to improve and how you can with your team to exploit them.

Fintech at WIZELINE

Software Engineer

Guadalajara, México 2023 - 2023

Working as the only FrontEnd engineer focused on optimizing the behavior and interactivity of a Web table.

- Improving the table loading passing from a 10-second load to only 1-second.
- Improving the interactions on the table work almost instantly comprising the previous 10 seconds waiting with every interaction.
- Leading the efforts to standardize the code to avoid repetitive types, duplicate functions, and misleading folder structure.

Fintech at WIZELINE

Guadalajara, México 2021 - 2023

Software Engineer

Working on an incremental migration of an old AngularJS App to a modern ReactJS approach. Leading the efforts to adopt a new design system.

- Implementing A/B testing and incremental UI releases with Optimizely.
- Using FullStory and Amplitude to track bugs.
- Implementing and leading the use of a new custom design system.
- Leading the efforts to slowly and incrementally restructure the code to make it more consistent.
- Working with RTL aiming for 70% coverage.
- Consuming REST API and also GraphQL.
- Leading the efforts to standardize the code to avoid repetitive types, duplicate functions, and misleading folder structure.

IBM

Web Developer

Guadalajara, México 2019 - 2021

Working maintaining a Java and React JS finantial application and also the migration from an oppromise server to a cloud solution

also the migration from an onpromise server to a cloud solution.

- Working with React JS and Java
- Working with OpenShit
- Maintain php and java legacy code

Agencia Espacial

Code Engineer

Guadalajara, México 2018 - 2019

Working on the whole development process from talking directly with clients to understand needs, to design and develop the solution.

- Working on the architecture and develop of multi platform solutions
- Having conversations directly with clients
- Fullstack PHP Developer
- Develop native iOS and android apps
- Implement online payment API

Rojo Advertising

PHP Developer

Durango, México 2017 - 2018

Develop and maintain web systems based on Laravel and WordPress

- Fullstack PHP Developer
- Having conversations directly with clients
- Develop custom solution